newspaperarchive.com 2003-12-09

# NewspaperArchive.com - Search old newspapers

|   

### Privacy Statement

##### NewspaperArchive.com Statement of Privacy:

NewspaperArchive.com recognizes the confidentiality of information that may be disclosed by members in registering or making purchases from our Website and we are firmly committed to protecting your privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this site. 

##### Overview:

The personal, private information that is provided to NewspaperArchive.com by individual members is not provided to unrelated third parties except in rare cases involving possible violations of our use policies or legal statutes. We do collect some data, always with your knowledge and consent, that is used to fulfill orders and otherwise enhance content to better meet the needs of our users. 

Information submitted by you online (such as your name, address, e-mail address) may be shared with companies with which NewspaperArchive.com has a commerce relationship and through which you reached this site, for marketing purposes. In such circumstances you will be considered their customer as well. If you object to such use, you may opt-out by e-mail request. Under no circumstances will NewspaperArchive.com share with any other party your password or other personal information it may acquire about children, family, etc. 

Demographic information collected through on-site user surveys may be used in aggregate statistical form to attract potential sponsors. 

The specifics of our Privacy Policy are best described in the answers to the following Frequently Asked Questions: 

##### Does NewspaperArchive.com ask for personal information?

Yes.   
NewspaperArchive.com asks for your name, e-mail address, and other limited personal information when you sign up as a member and use features such as e-mail. Most of this information may be entered at your discretion. We may ask for similar information at other times, such as when you enter sweepstakes or other promotions sponsored by NewspaperArchive.com and/or our many partners. 

##### How Does NewspaperArchive.com use my personal information?

Our goal is to provide you with the most personalized, relevant, user-friendly Web experience possible. The primary use of all your personal information is to efficiently provide you with relevant information. 

NewspaperArchive.com will also use registration information to let you know about new features or other offers of interest from NewspaperArchive.com, or to address customer service needs and requests. In distributing advertiser or sponsor messages, the advertiser never has access to individual account information. NewspaperArchive.com does not sell, rent or otherwise distribute the personal information you provide us to these advertisers. 

Advertisers simply provide an insertion order for the advertising message and NewspaperArchive.com then displays the ad to appropriate users based on the criteria specified in the order. 

##### Does NewspaperArchive.com request or require any personal financial information?

To facilitate payment and fulfillment for membership NewspaperArchive.com will request personal credit card or debit card information. In order to take advantage of other value-added family services that may be offered by NewspaperArchive.com in the future, users may be required to supply financial information. 

##### Will NewspaperArchive.com disclose any of my personal information to third parties?

NewspaperArchive.com will not disclose any of your personal information, except with your knowledge and consent as described in this policy or as may be required by law, or to protect the rights or property of NewspaperArchive.com. 

Circumstances where limited personal information may be disclosed are specifically described when the data is collected, such as in the User Agreement, or in the rules of sweepstakes or other promotions. So in all cases you control what, if any, information you disclose. 

NewspaperArchive.com reserves the right to disclose aggregated user statistics, such as "45% of our users are female" or "47% of our users earn $50,000 or more per year" in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties. Under protection of confidentiality agreements, NewspaperArchive.com may match common user information, such as name, address and phone number with third party data to avoid duplication and prevent errors. 

Additionally, if you click away from NewspaperArchive.com to visit the site of any third party advertiser or sponsor, you may be asked for your credit card or other personal information in order to purchase or use products and services offered. These companies have their own privacy and data collection practices. NewspaperArchive.com has no responsibility or liability for these independent policies. You should therefore review their privacy policies carefully if you have concerns about how your information may be used. 

##### Will NewspaperArchive.com use my information for direct mailings?

Only at your option.   
NewspaperArchive.com will occasionally send e-mail messages to advise members when new information has been posted to the Web site or to announce special product and service offerings that we feel may be of interest to you. If you do not want to receive such mailings, you may opt out at any time by using the unsubscribe link listed in the e-mail. 

##### May I refuse to provide personal information to NewspaperArchive.com or to accept advertising?

Yes and No.   
Visitors may access NewspaperArchive.com’s free services without providing any personal information. To gain full access to the members-only areas, a username, e-mail address and appropriate billing information are required. Because the NewspaperArchive.com site is partially advertiser supported, you may not "turn off" the advertising that appears on NewspaperArchive.com pages, but you may opt to be excluded from any e-mail advertising. Does NewspaperArchive.com use "IP Addresses"? IP Addresses:   
We do use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information such as geographic distribution of our members. NewspaperArchive.com Cookies: Contrary to popular myth, cookies do not extract private or personal information from your computer’s memory, but rather, record only information you volunteer to us upon registering or visiting the site. Cookies are tiny files placed onto the hard drive of your computer when you register at our Web site that enable our server to recognize or "remember" who you are each time you return. NewspaperArchive.com may make limited use of cookies to deliver content specific to your interests. For instance they may be used to retain your personal preferences or save your password so it doesn’t have to be re-entered each time you login. 

##### Advertiser Cookies:

NewspaperArchive.com does post third party advertising banners on personal family Web sites and on NewspaperArchive.com general use pages. These ads may contain cookies used primarily to provide data to the advertiser about where visitors are coming from. While we do use cookies in other parts of our Web site as explained above, cookies received with banner ads may or may not be collected by our company or be under our control. 

##### Are Chat room dialogues recorded and saved?

Chat is not currently offered at NewspaperArchive.com but will be in the future. Dialogues will NOT be collected, stored, or used by the company or others. 

##### What else should I know about privacy?

Demographic data is collected at our site at the users’ option. This information may include age and gender and other personal preferences that can be viewed and tabulated for use in marketing NewspaperArchive.com to advertisers and others. In no case is personal information given or sold to third parties. NewspaperArchive.com controls the distribution of ALL information at the site. 

##### Contests & Promotions

NewspaperArchive.com may occasionally run contests or other special promotions on our site in which we ask members or visitors for contact information (like an e-mail address) or demographic information (like a zip code, age, or income level). We use this data to send users promotional material about our company or our partners. The customer's contact information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary and may be shared with other companies for promotional purposes, but only with your prior permission and under the terms and conditions specified when you take part in the promotion. At any time, users may opt-out of receiving future mailings of this kind, or simply decline to take part in the promotions. 

##### Contacting the Website

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Website, you can contact: NewspaperArchive, inc 4049 21st ave sw Cedar Rapids, IA 52404   
  
---|---  
|   | 

* * *  
  
---|---  
  | **Frequently Asked Questions** | |  | **Tell A Friend** | |  | **Technical Support** | |  | **Online Support** | |  | **Feedback**  
  | Terms and Conditions | Privacy Policy | **© 2003 Heritage Microfilm, Inc.Copyright Info**
